

# Eric Beltran

emedia@ericbeltran.com www.ericbeltran.com 541.515.0357 Portland, OR MULTIMEDIA DESIGNER

#### **PROFILE**

Multimedia design graduate with strong technical skills and expertise in a variety of design applications. Excellent communicator, organizer, and problem solver. Quick learner, with a demonstrated ability to meet deadlines and work well in fast-paced or demanding environments.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## DIGITAL ARTIST >> FREELANCE

University of Oregon, 2004-2007

- Produced online promotional videos, designed posters, brochures, and t-shirts for the University's 'Foreign Language and International Studies Day', averaging 1,000 participants annually.
- Designed logo for new online foreign language development tool, 'Amiga', available to all instructors at the University of Oregon.
- Authored custom DVD series for permanent display at the Williams Bird Museum in Bali, India.

## TECHNICAL CONSULTANT >> CENTER FOR EDUCATIONAL TECHNOLOGIES

University of Oregon, 2005-07

- Provided campus-wide technical support for all educational software and hardware needs.
- Assisted faculty with web production, video editting, audio sweeting and provided necessary graphics support.
- Demonstrated strong ability in prioritizing multiple projects and meeting deadlines while maintaining attention to detail and producing quality work.

## INSTRUCTIONAL TECHNOLOGIST >> FACULTY MEDIA WORKSHOPS

University of Oregon, 2004-07

- Instructed faculty in Adobe Creative Suite programs during summer media workshops.
- Modeled strong ability to maintain patience and offer trouble-shooting solutions during periods of technical difficulties.

## **EDUCATION**

#### University of Oregon

B.A. Multimedia Design, B.A. International Studies, June 2007

- 3.78 GPA for multimedia major (4.0 scale)
- · Deans List, Spring 2007
- Study abroad term, Rosario, Argentina, Fall 2006

#### **PROGRAMS**

Adobe Photoshop, InDesign, Illustrator, Acrobat Professional, Flash, Dreamweaver, Fireworks Final Cut Pro, DVD Studio Pro, Soundtrack Pro, Compressor, Motion

Autodesk Combustion (equivelant to Shake)

Actionscript 2.0, basic HTML, Mac and Windows operating systems, troubleshooting and networking

## **AWARDS**

## UO DIGITAL ART EXPLOSION FESTIVAL

Animation piece selected for competive media festitval, 2007.

#### LAVERNE KRAUSE GALLERY

Graphic work displayed during one week media show, 'Creative Mention' award, 2007.

## DOWNTWON INITIATIVE FOR THE VISUAL ARTS FILM FESTIVAL

· Video piece selected for entry into competive summer festival, 2006.